<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <generator>RSS Builder by B!Soft</generator>
        <title>Fairly One-Dimensional</title>
        <link>www.fairlyonedimensional.com</link>
        <description>Blog about all things data </description>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <webMaster>Ari Morcos</webMaster>
        <copyright>Ari Morcos</copyright>
        <item>
            <title>
                Mining my google search history for clues, Part I
            </title>
            <pubDate>
                Sun, 29 Jun 2015 20:17:33 -0500
            </pubDate>
            <link>
                http://www.arimorcos.com/blog/post/Mining%20my%20google%20search%20history%20for%20clues%2C%20Part%20I/
            </link>
            <author>
                Ari Morcos
            </author>
            <description>
                We all have intensely personal relationships with Google. The questions we ask of it can, in many ways, tell the story of our lives. Ranging from questions about our work to our hobbies to our fears, many people are honest with Google in a way they are with a select few. I recently found out that Google allows users to download a record of the search queries in easily digestible JSON, and I immediately knew that this would be the topic of my next blog post. Pretending that I know nothing about myself, what can I learn about my life by looking through my search history? In part one of this two-part post, I'll explore the general themes present in my queries. What words appear the most often in my searches? How have my searches changed over the past two years? How about over the course of a week? Let's find out.
            </description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
                Sentiment analysis of movie taglines
            </title>
            <pubDate>
                Tue, 16 Jun 2015 20:17:33 -0500
            </pubDate>
            <link>
                http://www.arimorcos.com/blog/post/Sentiment%20analysis%20of%20movie%20taglines/
            </link>
            <author>
                Ari Morcos
            </author>
            <description>
                I recently came across Randal Olson's excellent post on how the usage of sex, drugs, violence, and cursing in movies have changed over time. This article led me to start thinking: how else have movies changed over time? Has the content of movie taglines (such as "The park is open." for Jurassic World or "Some men dream the future. He built it." for The Aviator) changed over time? In particular, have movie taglines gotten more negative?
            </description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
                Clustering subreddits by common word usage
            </title>
            <pubDate>
                Fri, 26 Mar 2015 12:17:33 -0500
            </pubDate>
            <link>
                http://www.arimorcos.com/blog/post/Clustering%20subreddits%20by%20common%20word%20usage/
            </link>
            <author>
                Ari Morcos
            </author>
            <description>
                What defines a subreddit? There are some obvious answers: topic, content type (images, videos, self-posts, or all of the above), and user population. For example, by topic, one might expect subreddits related to video games to be more similar to one another than any of them are to /r/politics. By content type, it seems reasonable to assume that self-post only subreddits like /r/AskHistorians and /r/AskScience are more similar to one another than either is /r/AdviceAnimals. But are there more subtle differences between subreddits that can be used to group them in meaningful ways as well? Do users of the different subreddits write in distinct, predictable fashion? Let's find out.
            </description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
                Creating a reddit dataset
            </title>
            <pubDate>
                Fri, 13 Mar 2015 12:17:33 -0500
            </pubDate>
            <link>
                http://www.arimorcos.com/blog/post/Creating%20a%20Reddit%20Dataset/
            </link>
            <author>
                Ari Morcos
            </author>
            <description>
                In preparation for the first set of analyses I'm planning for this blog, I spent some time over the last week preparing a package to create data sets from reddit. The package will collect comments and posts from specified subreddits within a custom date range and save it to a sqlite3 database for later analysis.
            </description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
                Hello World!
            </title>
            <pubDate>
                Tue, 24 Feb 2015 12:17:33 -0500
            </pubDate>
            <link>
                http://www.arimorcos.com/blog/post/Hello%20World%21/
            </link>
            <author>
                Ari Morcos
            </author>
            <description>
                Hello internet! Welcome to Fairly One-Dimensional, my blog about finding patterns in complex datasets. My goal is to post a new analysis of some freely available dataset every week or two (assuming my research allows me the time).
            </description>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>